A Finding Aid to the Linda Nochlin Papers, circa 1876, 1937-2017, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Writing Project Files, circa 1876; 1953-2016; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 17 Linear feet Boxes 7-21, 30-31, 33-34, OVs 36-37; 3.72 Gigabytes ER012-ER102
  - Files on Gustave Courbet and Realism, circa 1876; 1959-2010; 4.1; Archival Resource Key
    - "La Toilette de la Mariée", Correspondence, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - "La Toilette de la Mariée", Drafts, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - "La Toilette de la Mariée", Footnotes, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - "La Toilette de la Mariée", Images of Artwork, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - "La Toilette de la Mariée", Lecture at Vassar College, 1968-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - "La Toilette de la Mariée", List of Illustrations, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - "La Toilette de la Mariée", Notes, circa 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - "La Toilette de la Mariée", Research, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - "Why Courbet Now in the United States," Manuscript, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Files on Bathers and the Body, 1980-2005; 4.2; Archival Resource Key
    Nochlin's writings in this subseries relate to depictions of the human body, particularly female nudes. Many of the writings were originally presented by Nochlin during the 2004 Charles Eliot Norton Lecture Series and subsequently published in the 2006 book Bathers, Bodies, Beauty: The Visceral Eye. Earlier material titled "Bathers" or "Bathtime" is the product of her National Endowment for the Humanities award granted in 1993 to research the representation and practices of bathing in 19th-century France. The folders contain drafts, typescripts, lectures and presentation materials, correspondence, and research material. Additional material can be found within the teaching files in series 6, subseries 6.1.
    - "Bathers (Bath Time)," Digital Drafts, 1992; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 2 computer files (Folder ER015)
    - "Bathers (Bath Time)," Outline and Notes, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - "Bathers (Bath Time)," Research, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - "Bathers (Bath Time)," Typescripts, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - "Bathtime," Bibliography, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - "Bathtime," Bibliographies, 1991-1992; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 3 computer files (Folder ER016)
    - "Bathtime," Illustration Lists, 1991-1992; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 5 computer files (Folder ER017)
    - "Bathtime," Lectures, 1987-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - "Bathtime," Lecture Drafts and Outlines, 1990-1992; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 12 computer files (Folder ER018)
    - "Bath-time," Preliminary Outline for National Endowment for the Humanities, 1991; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER019)
    - "Bath-time," Proposal for National Endowment for the Humanities Summer Stipends Program, circa 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - "Bathtime: Renoir, Cézanne, Daumier and the Practices of Bathing in Nineteenth-Century France," Drafts, 1992-2004; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 3 computer files (Folder ER020)
    - "Bathtime: Renoir, Cézanne, Daumier and the Practices of Bathing in Nineteenth-Century France," Invoice for Research Material, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - "Bathtime: Renoir, Cézanne, Daumier and the Practices of Bathing in Nineteenth-Century France," Lecture and Printed Copy, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - "Bathtime: Renoir, Cézanne, Daumier and the Practices of Bathing in Nineteenth-Century France," Typescripts, circa 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - "The Body in Pieces," Correspondence, 1994-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - "The Body in Pieces," Neurath Lecture Drafts and Notes, 1992-1996; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 8 computer files (Folder ER021)
    - "The Body in Pieces," Outlines, 1993-1996; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 3 computer files (Folder ER022)
    - "The Body in Pieces," Proofs, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - "The Body in Pieces," Research, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - "The Body in Pieces," Research, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - "The Body in Pieces," Research, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - "The Body in Pieces," Typescripts, 1993-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - "Bonnard: The Bathers," Manuscripts and Notes, 1997-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Bonnard Exhibition Press Material, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Bonnard Exhibition, "Seeing Bonnard" by John Elderfield - Catalog Proof, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Cézanne's Bathers Research, 1980-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Cézanne's Bathers Research, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Cézanne's Bathers Research, 1992; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 2 computer files (Folder ER023)
    - "Degas vs. Cézanne: Indoor Bath and Outdoor Bathers," Lecture Notes, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - "Degas Versus Cézanne: Issues of Form, Content, and Context," Manuscript and Research, 1996-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - "Degas Versus Cézanne: Issues of Form, Content, and Context," Manuscript and Research, 1996-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - "Destructions," Research, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Lists of Artwork in Salons During the 1800s, circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - "The Man in the Bathtub," Digital Prints, 2003-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - "The Man in the Bathtub," Lectures, 2003-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - "The Man in the Bathtub," Lecture Drafts, 2000-2004; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 4 computer files (Folder ER025)
    - "The Man in the Bathtub," Lecture Presentation Material, 1997-2005; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records, see ER025 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - "Manet's Le Bain," Lecture at CAA in New York City, 1993-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - "Manet's Le Bain," Lecture at Musée du Louvre, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - "Manet's Le Bain," Typescripts, 1995-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - "Manet's Le Bain," Typescripts, 2004-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - "Manet's Le Bain," Various Draft Versions, 1992-2004; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 22 computer files (Folder ER026)
    - "Memories of Bathing: Bathtimes," Drafts, 1991-1992; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 4 computer files (Folder ER024)
    - "Monet's Hôtel des Roches Noires: Anxiety and Perspective at the Seashore," Lecture, 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - "Monet's Hôtel des Roches Noires: Anxiety and Perspective at the Seashore," Notes and Drafts, 1991-2004; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 9 computer files (Folder ER027)
    - "Nude but Not Naughty: Victorian Artists Confront the Body," Draft, 2002; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER028)
    - "Pioneering Modern Painting: Cézanne and Pissaro and the Representation of Women" at MOMA, Digital Audio Recording, 2005; Archival Resource Key; 0.614 Gigabytes 2 computer files (Folder ER029)
    - "Pissarro, Cézanne and the Representation of Women," Drafts and Research, 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - "Real Beauty: The Body in Realism," Lectures, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - "Real Beauty: The Body in Realism," Outline Fragments, 2004; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 2 computer files (Folder ER030)
    - "Renoir's Great Bathers: Bathing as Practice, Bathing as Representation," Digital Drafts, 2004; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 3 computer files (Folder ER032)
    - "Renoir's Great Bathers: Bathing as Practice, Bathing as Representation," Digital Lecture Image Lists, 1992-2004; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes (Folder ER031)
    - "Renoir's Great Bathers: Bathing as Practice, Bathing as Representation," Lecture Image Material, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - "Renoir's Great Bathers: Bathing as Practice, Bathing as Representation," Research, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - "Renoir's Great Bathers: Bathing as Practice, Bathing as Representation," Typescripts, 1990-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Research on Bathers, circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Research on Bathers, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Research on Bathers, 1991-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Research, Digital Notes Related to Bathers and Bathing, 1990-1993; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 19 computer files (Folder ER033)
    - Research, Notebook on Baths in France, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Research, Notebook on Baths in France, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Research on Trouville Baths, 1993-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Research on Trouville Baths, circa 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - "Violet, Yellow, and Marie-Thérèse," Galley Draft, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Essays, 1953-2012; 4.3; Archival Resource Key
    This subseries contains published and unpublished essay project material that falls outside of Nochlin's Courbet and bathers work. Many of the essays deal with gender and feminism, but Nochlin also discusses topics such as anti-Semitism, labor rights, furniture design, and art theory in several of the essays. Essay drafts and accompanying exhibition material for Global Feminisms, a major feminist art exhibition co-curated by Nochlin and Maura Reilly, are also included in this subseries.
    - "Art and Its Audience: A Personal View", 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - "Art and Its Audience: A Personal View", 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - "Art and the Conditions of Exile: Men/Women, Emigration/Expatriation," Digital Draft, 1996; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER034)
    - "Art and the Conditions of Exile: Men/Women, Emigration/Expatriation", 1993-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - "Art and the Conditions of Exile: Men/Women, Emigration/Expatriation", circa 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - "Bernice Abbott", 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - "The Big Picture: Scale, Style and Meaning in Modern Art", 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - "The Case of the Woman Warrior: Gender, Violence and Allegory in the Art of the French Revolution," Draft (1 of 2), 1989-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - "The Case of the Woman Warrior: Gender, Violence and Allegory in the Art of the French Revolution," Draft (2 of 2), 1989-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - "The Case of the Woman Warrior: Gender, Violence and Allegory in the Art of the French Revolution," Illustrations, circa 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - "The Case of the Woman Warrior: Gender, Violence and Allegory in the Art of the French Revolution," Related Material, circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - "The Case of the Woman Warrior: Gender, Violence and Allegory in the Art of the French Revolution," Research, circa 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - "Cassatt, Eakins, and the Issue of Gender in Nineteenth-Century American Painting," Digital Drafts and Notes, 1993-1995; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 4 computer files (Folder ER035)
    - "The Colonial Viewfinder," Correspondence and Research, 1985-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - "The Colonial Viewfinder," Drafts, circa 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - "The Colonial Viewfinder," Drafts and Notes, circa 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - "Cézanne: The Late Work", 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - "Cora Cohen: Recent Paintings", 1992-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - "The Cribleuses de Blé: Courbet, Millet, Breton, Kollwitz, and the Image of the Working Woman", 1979-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - "The Cribleuses de Blé: Courbet, Millet, Breton, Kollwitz, and the Image of the Working Woman," Drafts, 1995; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER037)
    - "The Darwin Effect", 2001-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - "The Darwin Effect: Introduction," Drafts and Outlines, 2001-2003; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 6 computer files (Folder ER038)
    - "Degas and the Dreyfus Affair: A Portrait of the Artist as an Anti-Semite," Annotated Book, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - "Degas and the Dreyfus Affair: A Portrait of the Artist as an Anti-Semite," Drafts, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - "Degas and the Dreyfus Affair: A Portrait of the Artist as an Anti-Semite," Lecture at Metropolitan Museum of Art, circa 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - "Degas and the Dreyfus Affair: A Portrait of the Artist as an Anti-Semite," Research, circa 1986-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - "Degas and the Dreyfus Affair: A Portrait of the Artist as an Anti-Semite," Research, 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - "Delacroix's Liberty: Daumier's Republic: Gender Advertisements in Nineteenth-Century Political Allegory," Drafts, circa 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - "Delacroix's Liberty: Daumier's Republic: Gender Advertisements in Nineteenth-Century Political Allegory," Draft, 1995; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER039)
    - "Delacroix's Liberty: Daumier's Republic: Gender Advertisements in Nineteenth-Century Political Allegory," Research, 1968-circa 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - "Documenta/Documentary: Some Thoughts on the Big Show at Kassel", 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - "Dorothy Richardson's Pilgrimage: The Feminine Novel," Drafts, circa 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - "Dorothy Richardson's Pilgrimage: The Feminine Novel," Research, circa 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - "The Dreamy Worlds of Emile Gallé", 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - "Edward Hopper and the Imagery of Alienation," Research, 1968-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - "Edward Hopper and the Imagery of Alienation", circa 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - "Fantin-Latour: Portrait Painter of the Avant-Garde", 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Florine Stettheimer, Correspondence, 1973-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Florine Stettheimer, Drafts, 1975-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Florine Stettheimer, Note Cards on Androgyny and Social Consciousness (1 of 2), circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Florine Stettheimer, Note Cards on Androgyny and Social Consciousness (2 of 2), circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Florine Stettheimer, Research, 1975-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - "Gericault's Raft of Medusa", circa 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Global Feminisms Exhibition, Checklists, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Global Feminisms Exhibition, Checklists, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Global Feminisms Exhibition, Correspondence, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Global Feminisms Exhibition, Drafts, 2002-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Global Feminisms Exhibition, Digital Materials, 2004-2005; Archival Resource Key; 0.08 Gigabytes 9 computer files (Folder ER040)
    - Global Feminisms Exhibition, Proposals and Outlines, 2004-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Global Feminisms Exhibition, Research, 2004-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Global Feminisms Exhibition, Typescript for Panel Discussion at Brooklyn Museum of Art, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - "Fashion in Painting", 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - "Furniture Moves: The New Artists' Furniture", 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - "A House is not a Home: Degas and the Subversion of the Family", 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - "A House is not a Home: Degas and the Subversion of the Family," Draft, 1995; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER041)
    - "Impressionist Portraits and the construction of Modern Identity", 1995-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - "Impressionist Portraits and the Construction of Modern Identity", 1996; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 36)
    - "Impressionist Portraits and the construction of Modern Identity," Drafts and Notes, 1996; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 4 computer files (Folder ER042)
    - "Invention of Avant-Garde Art", 1969-1970; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 36)
    - "Invention of Avant-Garde Art", circa 1970-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - "Kate Millet: Sculpture Show" Exhibition Catalog Preface, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - "Kate Millet: Sculpture Show" Exhibition Catalog Preface Drafts, 1996; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 2 computer files (Folder ER043)
    - "Léon Frédéric: Stages of a Worker's Life," Drafts and Notes, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - "Léon Frédéric: Stages of a Worker's Life," Research, 1979-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - "Lost and Found: Once More the Fallen Woman," Correspondence with Howard Hibbard, 1977-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - "Lost and Found: Once More the Fallen Woman," Drafts, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - "Lost and Found: Once More the Fallen Woman," Images, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - "Lost and Found: Once More the Fallen Woman," Notes, circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - "Lost and Found: Once More the Fallen Woman," Notes, circa 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - "Lost and Found: Once More the Fallen Woman," Press, circa 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - "Lost and Found: Once More the Fallen Woman," Research, circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - "Lost and Found: Once More the Fallen Woman," Research, circa 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - "Lost and Found: Once More the Fallen Woman," Research on Rosetti, circa 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - "Manet's Ball at the Opera," Correspondence, 1977-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - "Manet's Ball at the Opera," Drafts, circa 1975-circa 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - "Manet's Ball at the Opera," Notes, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 36)
    - "Manet's Ball at the Opera," Notes, circa 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - "Manet's Ball at the Opera," Notes, circa 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - "Manet's Ball at the Opera," Notebook, circa 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - "Manet's Ball at the Opera," Notebook, circa 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - "Manet's Ball at the Opera," Research, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - "Manet's Ball at the Opera," Research, circa 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Manet, Miscellaneous Notes, circa 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Manet and the Sea, Symposium in Philadelphia, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - "Manet Still Life", 2000-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - "Manet Still Life," Drafts and Notes, 2000-2001; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 9 computer files (Folder ER047)
    - Manet, Symposium at Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - "Mathis at Colmar: A Visual Confrontation", circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - "Modernity: An Alternative Vision: 'Faces in the Crowd' at the Whitechapel Gallery", 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - "Modernity: An Alternative Vision: 'Faces in the Crowd' at the Whitechapel Gallery," Drafts, 2005; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 5 computer files (Folder ER044)
    - "The Myth of the Woman Warrior: 18th to 20th-Century Representations of fighting and Powerful Women of the French Revolution," Drafts, 1995-1997; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 3 computer files (Folder ER036)
    - "Naked at the Tate: Reviewing the Modern Nude", 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - "'The New Painting': A New Way of Looking at Impressionism", 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - "New Tricks for an Old Dog: The Return of Painting", 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - "New Tricks for an Old Dog: The Return of Painting"/"Painting Today," Drafts, 2003; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 10 computer files (Folder ER045)
    - "The Paterson Strike Pageant of 1913", 1974-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - "The Paterson Strike Pageant of 1913," Note Card Book, circa 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - "The Paterson Strike Pageant of 1913," Note Cards, circa 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - "The Paterson Strike Pageant of 1913," Research, circa 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - "The Paterson Strike Pageant of 1913," Research, circa 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - "Picasso - DeKooning at C and M", 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - "Pissarro: The Unassuming Eye", 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - "The Recent Work of Miriam Shapiro," Drafts, 1973-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - "The Recent Work of Miriam Shapiro," Notes, circa 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - "The Recent Work of Miriam Shapiro," Note Card Book, circa 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - "The Recent Work of Miriam Shapiro," Research, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - "Repose: Three Paintings from the Fin-de-Siècle", circa 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - "The Room in Art", 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - "Rupert Garcia: The Power of the Image", 1995-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - "The Sculpture of Olga Bernal," Draft, 2000; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER046)
    - "The Sculpture of Olga Bernal", 2000-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - "The Seductions of the Small: Simonds, the Poiriers, Shapiro", 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - "Self as Art Object", circa 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - "Seurat's Grand Jatte: An Anti-Utopian Allegory," Correspondence, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 28)